[
{"Front": "愛", "Back": "あい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挨拶", "Back": "あいさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愛情", "Back": "あいじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合図", "Back": "あいず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愛する", "Back": "あいする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相手", "Back": "あいて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明かり", "Back": "あかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空き", "Back": "あき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明らか", "Back": "あきらか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諦める", "Back": "あきらめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飽きる", "Back": "あきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "握手", "Back": "あくしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪魔", "Back": "あくま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明ける", "Back": "あける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "預ける", "Back": "あずける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汗", "Back": "あせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "与える", "Back": "あたえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暖かい", "Back": "あたたか(い)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辺り", "Back": "あたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当たる", "Back": "あたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扱う", "Back": "あつかう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集まり", "Back": "あつまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当てる", "Back": "あてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跡", "Back": "あと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "穴", "Back": "あな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浴びる", "Back": "あびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "油", "Back": "あぶら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余り", "Back": "あまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誤り", "Back": "あやまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粗", "Back": "あら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嵐", "Back": "あらし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新た", "Back": "あらた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "表す", "Back": "あらわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現す", "Back": "あらわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現れ", "Back": "あらわれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現れる", "Back": "あらわれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有る", "Back": "ある", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "或", "Back": "ある", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泡", "Back": "あわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合わせる", "Back": "あわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "哀れ", "Back": "あわれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "案", "Back": "あん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暗記", "Back": "あんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "安定", "Back": "あんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "案内", "Back": "あんない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "胃", "Back": "い", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "いえ", "Back": "いえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "委員", "Back": "いいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言う", "Back": "ゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意外", "Back": "いがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行き", "Back": "いき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "息", "Back": "いき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勢い", "Back": "いきおい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生き物", "Back": "いきもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幾つ", "Back": "いくつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幾ら", "Back": "いくら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "医師", "Back": "いし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意思", "Back": "いし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意志", "Back": "いし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "維持", "Back": "いじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意識", "Back": "いしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異常", "Back": "いじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "椅子", "Back": "いす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泉", "Back": "いずみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "以前", "Back": "いぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "板", "Back": "いた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偉大", "Back": "いだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抱く", "Back": "いだく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頂く", "Back": "いただく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "痛み", "Back": "いたみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "至る", "Back": "いたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "位置", "Back": "いち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一時", "Back": "いちじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一度に", "Back": "いちどに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "市場", "Back": "いちば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一番", "Back": "いちばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一家", "Back": "いっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一種", "Back": "いっしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一瞬", "Back": "いっしゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一生", "Back": "いっしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一層", "Back": "いっそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一体", "Back": "いったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一致", "Back": "いっち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一般", "Back": "いっぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一方", "Back": "いっぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "いつも", "Back": "いつも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "移動", "Back": "いどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従兄弟", "Back": "いとこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "稲", "Back": "いね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "居眠り", "Back": "いねむり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "命", "Back": "いのち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "違反", "Back": "いはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衣服", "Back": "いふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "居間", "Back": "いま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今に", "Back": "いまに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今にも", "Back": "いまにも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "否", "Back": "いや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "以来", "Back": "いらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "依頼", "Back": "いらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "医療", "Back": "いりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "岩", "Back": "いわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祝い", "Back": "いわい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祝う", "Back": "いわう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言わば", "Back": "いわば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "印刷", "Back": "いんさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "印象", "Back": "いんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引退", "Back": "いんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引用", "Back": "いんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上", "Back": "うわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "魚", "Back": "うお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伺う", "Back": "うかがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け取る", "Back": "うけとる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動かす", "Back": "うごかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兎", "Back": "うさぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "牛", "Back": "うし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "失う", "Back": "うしなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "後", "Back": "うしろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嘘", "Back": "うそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疑う", "Back": "うたがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内", "Back": "うち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宇宙", "Back": "うちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "撃つ", "Back": "うつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "移す", "Back": "うつす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訴える", "Back": "うったえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奪う", "Back": "うばう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馬", "Back": "うま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "うまい", "Back": "うまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生まれ", "Back": "うまれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "梅", "Back": "うめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裏切る", "Back": "うらぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嬉しい", "Back": "うれしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売れる", "Back": "うれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "噂", "Back": "うわさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "うん", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運", "Back": "うん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運転", "Back": "うんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運動", "Back": "うんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "柄", "Back": "え", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "永遠", "Back": "えいえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "永久", "Back": "えいきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "影響", "Back": "えいきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "営業", "Back": "えいぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衛星", "Back": "えいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "栄養", "Back": "えいよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "笑顔", "Back": "えがお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "描く", "Back": "えがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "餌", "Back": "えさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "得る", "Back": "える", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "円", "Back": "えん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "延期", "Back": "えんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演技", "Back": "えんぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "援助", "Back": "えんじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演説", "Back": "えんぜつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演奏", "Back": "えんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遠慮", "Back": "えんりょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御", "Back": "お", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "老い", "Back": "おい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追い付く", "Back": "おいつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "王", "Back": "おう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追う", "Back": "おう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "王様", "Back": "おうさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "王子", "Back": "おうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応じる", "Back": "おうじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "横断", "Back": "おうだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終える", "Back": "おえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大いに", "Back": "おおいに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覆う", "Back": "おおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大家", "Back": "おおや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丘", "Back": "おか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沖", "Back": "おき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奥", "Back": "おく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "贈る", "Back": "おくる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "起こる", "Back": "おこる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幼い", "Back": "おさない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収める", "Back": "おさめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汚染", "Back": "おせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐れる", "Back": "おそれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐ろしい", "Back": "おそろしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お互い", "Back": "おたがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "穏やか", "Back": "おだやか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "男の人", "Back": "おとこのひと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "劣る", "Back": "おとる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お腹", "Back": "おなか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鬼", "Back": "おに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "帯", "Back": "おび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お昼", "Back": "おひる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溺れる", "Back": "おぼれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お目に掛かる", "Back": "おめにかかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思い出", "Back": "おもいで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主に", "Back": "おもに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思わず", "Back": "おもわず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泳ぎ", "Back": "およぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "及ぼす", "Back": "およぼす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "居る", "Back": "おる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下す", "Back": "おろす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "降ろす", "Back": "おろす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終", "Back": "おわり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "音", "Back": "おん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恩", "Back": "おん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "温暖", "Back": "おんだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "温度", "Back": "おんど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可", "Back": "か", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "課", "Back": "か", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会", "Back": "かい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回", "Back": "かい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "害", "Back": "がい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会員", "Back": "かいいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絵画", "Back": "かいが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海外", "Back": "かいがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会計", "Back": "かいけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解決", "Back": "かいけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会合", "Back": "かいごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外交", "Back": "がいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開始", "Back": "かいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解釈", "Back": "かいしゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外出", "Back": "がいしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改善", "Back": "かいぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "快適", "Back": "かいてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回復", "Back": "かいふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飼う", "Back": "かう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "替える", "Back": "かえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "換える", "Back": "かえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "香り", "Back": "かおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "画家", "Back": "がか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抱える", "Back": "かかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "価格", "Back": "かかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化学", "Back": "かがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輝く", "Back": "かがやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "係", "Back": "かかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掛かる", "Back": "かかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "罹る", "Back": "かかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鍵", "Back": "かぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "限る", "Back": "かぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家具", "Back": "かぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学", "Back": "がく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "額", "Back": "がく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覚悟", "Back": "かくご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確実", "Back": "かくじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学者", "Back": "がくしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学習", "Back": "がくしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隠す", "Back": "かくす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拡大", "Back": "かくだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確認", "Back": "かくにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学問", "Back": "がくもん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隠れる", "Back": "かくれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "影", "Back": "かげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陰", "Back": "かげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欠ける", "Back": "かける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加減", "Back": "かげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過去", "Back": "かこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "籠", "Back": "かご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "囲む", "Back": "かこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火災", "Back": "かさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貸し", "Back": "かし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "菓子", "Back": "かし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家事", "Back": "かじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賢い", "Back": "かしこい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歌手", "Back": "かしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "数", "Back": "かず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "稼ぐ", "Back": "かせぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "数える", "Back": "かぞえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "型", "Back": "かた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肩", "Back": "かた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "硬い", "Back": "かたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方々", "Back": "かたがた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刀", "Back": "かたな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "語る", "Back": "かたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勝ち", "Back": "かち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "価値", "Back": "かち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活気", "Back": "かっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学期", "Back": "がっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "格好", "Back": "かっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活動", "Back": "かつどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活用", "Back": "かつよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悲しむ", "Back": "かなしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "必ずしも", "Back": "かならずしも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金", "Back": "かね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金持ち", "Back": "かねもち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可能", "Back": "かのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "株", "Back": "かぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "被る", "Back": "かぶる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "構う", "Back": "かまう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "我慢", "Back": "がまん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神", "Back": "かみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雷", "Back": "かみなり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "髪の毛", "Back": "かみのけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "科目", "Back": "かもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火曜", "Back": "かよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空", "Back": "から", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刈る", "Back": "かる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彼等", "Back": "かれら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "川", "Back": "かわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "河", "Back": "かわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皮", "Back": "かわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "革", "Back": "かわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "缶", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勘", "Back": "かん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "考え", "Back": "かんがえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感覚", "Back": "かんかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観客", "Back": "かんきゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "環境", "Back": "かんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歓迎", "Back": "かんげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観光", "Back": "かんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観察", "Back": "かんさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感じ", "Back": "かんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感謝", "Back": "かんしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "患者", "Back": "かんじゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勘定", "Back": "かんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感情", "Back": "かんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感じる", "Back": "かんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感心", "Back": "かんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関心", "Back": "かんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関する", "Back": "かんする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "完成", "Back": "かんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "完全", "Back": "かんぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感動", "Back": "かんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "監督", "Back": "かんとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "管理", "Back": "かんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "完了", "Back": "かんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関連", "Back": "かんれん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議員", "Back": "ぎいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記憶", "Back": "きおく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気温", "Back": "きおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機械", "Back": "きかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議会", "Back": "ぎかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "期間", "Back": "きかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機関", "Back": "きかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "企業", "Back": "きぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "効く", "Back": "きく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機嫌", "Back": "きげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気候", "Back": "きこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "岸", "Back": "きし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生地", "Back": "きじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記事", "Back": "きじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "技師", "Back": "ぎし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記者", "Back": "きしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傷", "Back": "きず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "期待", "Back": "きたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "帰宅", "Back": "きたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貴重", "Back": "きちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議長", "Back": "ぎちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気付く", "Back": "きづく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気に入る", "Back": "きにいる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記入", "Back": "きにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記念", "Back": "きねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機能", "Back": "きのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気の毒", "Back": "きのどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寄付", "Back": "きふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "希望", "Back": "きぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基本", "Back": "きほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決まり", "Back": "きまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気味", "Back": "きみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "義務", "Back": "ぎむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奇妙", "Back": "きみょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疑問", "Back": "ぎもん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆", "Back": "ぎゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "九", "Back": "きゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旧", "Back": "きゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "級", "Back": "きゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "球", "Back": "きゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休暇", "Back": "きゅうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休憩", "Back": "きゅうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "急激", "Back": "きゅうげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吸収", "Back": "きゅうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "救助", "Back": "きゅうじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "急速", "Back": "きゅうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "急に", "Back": "きゅうに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "給料", "Back": "きゅうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "器用", "Back": "きよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教科書", "Back": "きょうかしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "競技", "Back": "きょうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行儀", "Back": "ぎょうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "供給", "Back": "きょうきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教師", "Back": "きょうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教授", "Back": "きょうじゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強調", "Back": "きょうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共通", "Back": "きょうつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共同", "Back": "きょうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐怖", "Back": "きょうふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "協力", "Back": "きょうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強力", "Back": "きょうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "許可", "Back": "きょか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "局", "Back": "きょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巨大", "Back": "きょだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嫌う", "Back": "きらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "霧", "Back": "きり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切れ", "Back": "きれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "切れる", "Back": "きれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記録", "Back": "きろく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "議論", "Back": "ぎろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "銀", "Back": "ぎん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "禁煙", "Back": "きんえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金額", "Back": "きんがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金庫", "Back": "きんこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "禁止", "Back": "きんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金銭", "Back": "きんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金属", "Back": "きんぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近代", "Back": "きんだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緊張", "Back": "きんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筋肉", "Back": "きんにく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金融", "Back": "きんゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金曜", "Back": "きんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "句", "Back": "く", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食う", "Back": "くう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偶然", "Back": "ぐうぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "臭い", "Back": "くさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鎖", "Back": "くさり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腐る", "Back": "くさる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "癖", "Back": "くせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "管", "Back": "くだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "具体", "Back": "ぐたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下さる", "Back": "くださる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下り", "Back": "くだり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦痛", "Back": "くつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区別", "Back": "くべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組", "Back": "くみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組合", "Back": "くみあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組む", "Back": "くむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曇", "Back": "くもり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "位", "Back": "くらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暮らし", "Back": "くらし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暮らす", "Back": "くらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繰り返す", "Back": "くりかえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "狂う", "Back": "くるう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦しい", "Back": "くるしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦しむ", "Back": "くるしむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暮れ", "Back": "くれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦労", "Back": "くろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加える", "Back": "くわえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詳しい", "Back": "くわしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加わる", "Back": "くわわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訓", "Back": "くん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍", "Back": "ぐん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軍隊", "Back": "ぐんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訓練", "Back": "くんれん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下", "Back": "げ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "計", "Back": "けい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敬意", "Back": "けいい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経営", "Back": "けいえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "計画", "Back": "けいかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "景気", "Back": "けいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経験", "Back": "けいけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾向", "Back": "けいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "警告", "Back": "けいこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "計算", "Back": "けいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掲示", "Back": "けいじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刑事", "Back": "けいじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芸術", "Back": "げいじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "契約", "Back": "けいやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経由", "Back": "けいゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怪我", "Back": "けが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "劇", "Back": "げき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "劇場", "Back": "げきじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "化粧", "Back": "けしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結果", "Back": "けっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欠陥", "Back": "けっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結局", "Back": "けっきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決心", "Back": "けっしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欠席", "Back": "けっせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "決定", "Back": "けってい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欠点", "Back": "けってん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月曜", "Back": "げつよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結論", "Back": "けつろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煙", "Back": "けむり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "券", "Back": "けん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "県", "Back": "けん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軒", "Back": "けん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喧嘩", "Back": "けんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見解", "Back": "けんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "限界", "Back": "げんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現金", "Back": "げんきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言語", "Back": "げんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "健康", "Back": "けんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "検査", "Back": "けんさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現在", "Back": "げんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現実", "Back": "げんじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現象", "Back": "げんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現状", "Back": "げんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "建設", "Back": "けんせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現代", "Back": "げんだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "建築", "Back": "けんちく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見当", "Back": "けんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "検討", "Back": "けんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現場", "Back": "げんば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憲法", "Back": "けんぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "権利", "Back": "けんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "語", "Back": "ご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恋", "Back": "こい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濃い", "Back": "こい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恋人", "Back": "こいびと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幸運", "Back": "こううん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "講演", "Back": "こうえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "効果", "Back": "こうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "硬貨", "Back": "こうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高価", "Back": "こうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "豪華", "Back": "ごうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合格", "Back": "ごうかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交換", "Back": "こうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "航空", "Back": "こうくう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "光景", "Back": "こうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合計", "Back": "ごうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "攻撃", "Back": "こうげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貢献", "Back": "こうけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広告", "Back": "こうこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交際", "Back": "こうさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "後者", "Back": "こうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工場", "Back": "こうば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "構成", "Back": "こうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高速", "Back": "こうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行動", "Back": "こうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強盗", "Back": "ごうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幸福", "Back": "こうふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公平", "Back": "こうへい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "候補", "Back": "こうほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "考慮", "Back": "こうりょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "越える", "Back": "こえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "氷", "Back": "こおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凍る", "Back": "こおる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誤解", "Back": "ごかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "語学", "Back": "ごがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呼吸", "Back": "こきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "故郷", "Back": "こきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "極", "Back": "ごく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国語", "Back": "こくご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "黒板", "Back": "こくばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "克服", "Back": "こくふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国民", "Back": "こくみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "穀物", "Back": "こくもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ここ", "Back": "ここ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腰", "Back": "こし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "故障", "Back": "こしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個人", "Back": "こじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "越す", "Back": "こす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国家", "Back": "こっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国会", "Back": "こっかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国境", "Back": "こっきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "骨折", "Back": "こっせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小包", "Back": "こづつみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事", "Back": "こと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "異なる", "Back": "ことなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "諺", "Back": "ことわざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "断る", "Back": "ことわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粉", "Back": "こな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "この", "Back": "この", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好み", "Back": "このみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好む", "Back": "このむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塵", "Back": "ごみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小麦", "Back": "こむぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小屋", "Back": "こや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頃", "Back": "ころ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殺す", "Back": "ころす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転ぶ", "Back": "ころぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今回", "Back": "こんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今後", "Back": "こんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混雑", "Back": "こんざつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "困難", "Back": "こんなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "今日", "Back": "こんにち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "婚約", "Back": "こんやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混乱", "Back": "こんらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差", "Back": "さ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "際", "Back": "さい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最高", "Back": "さいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "財産", "Back": "ざいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最終", "Back": "さいしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最中", "Back": "さいちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最低", "Back": "さいてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "才能", "Back": "さいのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裁判", "Back": "さいばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "材料", "Back": "ざいりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幸い", "Back": "さいわい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "境", "Back": "さかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆らう", "Back": "さからう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盛り", "Back": "さかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作業", "Back": "さぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昨", "Back": "さく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作品", "Back": "さくひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作物", "Back": "さくもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "桜", "Back": "さくら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酒", "Back": "さけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叫ぶ", "Back": "さけぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "避ける", "Back": "さける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支える", "Back": "ささえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指す", "Back": "さす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "座席", "Back": "ざせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誘う", "Back": "さそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "札", "Back": "さつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作家", "Back": "さっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作曲", "Back": "さっきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "砂漠", "Back": "さばく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差別", "Back": "さべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作法", "Back": "さほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "様々", "Back": "さまざま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覚ます", "Back": "さます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覚める", "Back": "さめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "左右", "Back": "さゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皿", "Back": "さら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "更に", "Back": "さらに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "去る", "Back": "さる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "猿", "Back": "さる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "騒ぎ", "Back": "さわぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "参加", "Back": "さんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "参考", "Back": "さんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賛成", "Back": "Uӣ[い", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酸素", "Back": "さんそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "散歩", "Back": "さんぽ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "四", "Back": "し", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "氏", "Back": "し", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詩", "Back": "し", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幸せ", "Back": "しあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ジェット機", "Back": "ジェットき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直に", "Back": "じかに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叱る", "Back": "しかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "式", "Back": "しき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直", "Back": "じき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時期", "Back": "じき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支給", "Back": "しきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刺激", "Back": "しげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "資源", "Back": "しげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事件", "Back": "じけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時刻", "Back": "じこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自殺", "Back": "じさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事実", "Back": "じじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支出", "Back": "ししゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事情", "Back": "じじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詩人", "Back": "しじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自身", "Back": "じしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "沈む", "Back": "しずむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自然", "Back": "しぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思想", "Back": "しそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "舌", "Back": "した", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "次第", "Back": "しだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事態", "Back": "じたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従う", "Back": "したがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "したがって", "Back": "したがって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支度", "Back": "したく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親しい", "Back": "したしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "七", "Back": "しち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "質", "Back": "しつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "失業", "Back": "しつぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実験", "Back": "じっけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実現", "Back": "じつげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実行", "Back": "じっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実際", "Back": "じっさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実施", "Back": "じっし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実に", "Back": "じつに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実は", "Back": "じつは", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "失望", "Back": "しつぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支店", "Back": "してん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指導", "Back": "しどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自動", "Back": "じどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "品", "Back": "しな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支配", "Back": "しはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芝居", "Back": "しばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芝生", "Back": "しばふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支払", "Back": "しはらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "支払う", "Back": "しはらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "死亡", "Back": "しぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "資本", "Back": "しほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "しまい", "Back": "（終わり）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姉妹", "Back": "しまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "しまう", "Back": "（終わる）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "しまった", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自慢", "Back": "じまん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "事務", "Back": "じむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "示す", "Back": "しめす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "占める", "Back": "しめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "霜", "Back": "しも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "借金", "Back": "しゃっきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "邪魔", "Back": "じゃま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "週", "Back": "しゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "州", "Back": "しゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "十", "Back": "じゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "銃", "Back": "じゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "周囲", "Back": "しゅうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収穫", "Back": "しゅうかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "週間", "Back": "しゅうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宗教", "Back": "しゅうきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重視", "Back": "じゅうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "就職", "Back": "しゅうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修正", "Back": "しゅうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "渋滞", "Back": "じゅうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重大", "Back": "じゅうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "住宅", "Back": "じゅうたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集団", "Back": "しゅうだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集中", "Back": "しゅうちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "収入", "Back": "しゅうにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "住民", "Back": "じゅうみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重要", "Back": "じゅうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修理", "Back": "しゅうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主義", "Back": "しゅぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宿泊", "Back": "しゅくはく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手術", "Back": "しゅじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "首相", "Back": "しゅしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手段", "Back": "しゅだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主張", "Back": "しゅちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出身", "Back": "しゅっしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出席", "Back": "しゅっせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出発", "Back": "しゅっぱつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出版", "Back": "しゅっぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "首都", "Back": "しゅと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主婦", "Back": "しゅふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主要", "Back": "しゅよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "需要", "Back": "じゅよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "種類", "Back": "しゅるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "順", "Back": "じゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瞬間", "Back": "しゅんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "順調", "Back": "じゅんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "順番", "Back": "じゅんばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "準備", "Back": "じゅんび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "使用", "Back": "しよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "章", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賞", "Back": "しょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "障害", "Back": "しょうがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "奨学金", "Back": "しょうがくきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗客", "Back": "じょうきゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上京", "Back": "じょうきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "状況", "Back": "じょうきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "条件", "Back": "じょうけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正午", "Back": "しょうご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正直", "Back": "しょうじき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "常識", "Back": "じょうしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少女", "Back": "しょうじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少々", "Back": "しょうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "症状", "Back": "しょうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生じる", "Back": "しょうじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "招待", "Back": "しょうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "状態", "Back": "じょうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上達", "Back": "じょうたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冗談", "Back": "じょうだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "承知", "Back": "しょうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上等", "Back": "じょうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衝突", "Back": "しょうとつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商人", "Back": "しょうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "承認", "Back": "しょうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少年", "Back": "しょうねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商売", "Back": "しょうばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消費", "Back": "しょうひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商品", "Back": "しょうひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消防", "Back": "しょうぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "情報", "Back": "じょうほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "証明", "Back": "しょうめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女王", "Back": "じょおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "職", "Back": "しょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "職業", "Back": "しょくぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食事", "Back": "しょくじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食卓", "Back": "しょくたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食品", "Back": "しょくひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "植物", "Back": "しょくぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食物", "Back": "しょくもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食欲", "Back": "しょくよく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食料", "Back": "しょくりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食糧", "Back": "しょくりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書斎", "Back": "しょさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女子", "Back": "じょし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助手", "Back": "じょしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徐々に", "Back": "じょじょに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "署名", "Back": "しょめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書物", "Back": "しょもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女優", "Back": "じょゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "処理", "Back": "しょり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書類", "Back": "しょるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知らせ", "Back": "しらせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尻", "Back": "しり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "印", "Back": "しるし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "城", "Back": "しろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進学", "Back": "しんがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神経", "Back": "しんけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真剣", "Back": "しんけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信仰", "Back": "しんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信号", "Back": "しんごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人工", "Back": "じんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "深刻", "Back": "しんこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "診察", "Back": "しんさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人種", "Back": "じんしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信じる", "Back": "しんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人生", "Back": "じんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親戚", "Back": "しんせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新鮮", "Back": "しんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心臓", "Back": "しんぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身体", "Back": "しんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身長", "Back": "しんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慎重", "Back": "しんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心配", "Back": "しんぱい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "審判", "Back": "しんぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人物", "Back": "じんぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進歩", "Back": "しんぽ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親友", "Back": "しんゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信用", "Back": "しんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信頼", "Back": "しんらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心理", "Back": "しんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人類", "Back": "じんるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巣", "Back": "す", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図", "Back": "ず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水準", "Back": "すいじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "推薦", "Back": "すいせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "随分", "Back": "ずいぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "睡眠", "Back": "すいみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "数字", "Back": "すうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "末", "Back": "すえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姿", "Back": "すがた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空く", "Back": "すく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "救う", "Back": "すくう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優れる", "Back": "すぐれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "少しも", "Back": "すこしも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過ごす", "Back": "すごす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筋", "Back": "すじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "進める", "Back": "すすめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勧める", "Back": "すすめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頭痛", "Back": "ずつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "既に", "Back": "すでに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素晴らしい", "Back": "すばらしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全て", "Back": "すべて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "済ませる", "Back": "すませる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "角", "Back": "すみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "すみません", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "為る", "Back": "する", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "すると", "Back": "すると", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鋭い", "Back": "するどい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "背", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "性", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所為", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "税", "Back": "ぜい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "性格", "Back": "せいかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正確", "Back": "せいかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世紀", "Back": "せいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "請求", "Back": "せいきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "税金", "Back": "ぜいきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清潔", "Back": "せいけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制限", "Back": "せいげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成功", "Back": "せいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生産", "Back": "せいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正式", "Back": "せいしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "精神", "Back": "せいしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成人", "Back": "せいじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "精々", "Back": "せいぜい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成績", "Back": "せいせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "製造", "Back": "せいぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "贅沢", "Back": "ぜいたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成長", "Back": "せいちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制度", "Back": "せいど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "青年", "Back": "せいねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "製品", "Back": "せいひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "政府", "Back": "せいふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生物", "Back": "せいぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生命", "Back": "せいめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整理", "Back": "せいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "咳", "Back": "せき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "石炭", "Back": "せきたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "責任", "Back": "せきにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "石油", "Back": "せきゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世間", "Back": "せけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "説", "Back": "せつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "積極的", "Back": "せっきょくてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "設計", "Back": "せっけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶対", "Back": "ぜったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "設備", "Back": "せつび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶滅", "Back": "ぜつめつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "節約", "Back": "せつやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "是非", "Back": "ぜひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "責める", "Back": "せめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世話", "Back": "せわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "善", "Back": "ぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全", "Back": "ぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全員", "Back": "ぜんいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "専攻", "Back": "せんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全国", "Back": "ぜんこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先日", "Back": "せんじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前者", "Back": "ぜんしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "選手", "Back": "せんしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前進", "Back": "ぜんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全然", "Back": "ぜんぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全体", "Back": "ぜんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "選択", "Back": "せんたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "そう", "Back": "そう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "象", "Back": "ぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "騒音", "Back": "そうおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増加", "Back": "ぞうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "操作", "Back": "そうさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掃除", "Back": "そうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "想像", "Back": "そうぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相続", "Back": "そうぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相談", "Back": "そうだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "装置", "Back": "そうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相当", "Back": "そうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "速度", "Back": "そくど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "そこ", "Back": "そこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "底", "Back": "そこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組織", "Back": "そしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "注ぐ", "Back": "そそぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "育つ", "Back": "そだつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "袖", "Back": "そで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "備える", "Back": "そなえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "その", "Back": "その", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "側", "Back": "そば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粗末", "Back": "そまつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "それ", "Back": "（接。感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "損", "Back": "そん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "損害", "Back": "そんがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尊敬", "Back": "そんけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "存在", "Back": "そんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尊重", "Back": "そんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "田", "Back": "た", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "他", "Back": "た", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対", "Back": "たい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大", "Back": "だい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "台", "Back": "だい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "題", "Back": "だい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体育", "Back": "たいいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体温", "Back": "たいおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大会", "Back": "たいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大気", "Back": "たいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代金", "Back": "だいきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退屈", "Back": "たいくつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滞在", "Back": "たいざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大使", "Back": "たいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大した", "Back": "たいした", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対象", "Back": "たいしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大臣", "Back": "だいじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対する", "Back": "たいする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大戦", "Back": "たいせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大抵", "Back": "たいてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "態度", "Back": "たいど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大統領", "Back": "だいとうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大半", "Back": "たいはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代表", "Back": "だいひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大部分", "Back": "だいぶぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大変", "Back": "たいへん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逮捕", "Back": "たいほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "太陽", "Back": "たいよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平ら", "Back": "たいら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代理", "Back": "だいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大陸", "Back": "たいりく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倒す", "Back": "たおす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "だが", "Back": "だが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "互い", "Back": "たがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宝", "Back": "たから", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "だから", "Back": "だから", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宅", "Back": "たく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確かめる", "Back": "たしかめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "多少", "Back": "たしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助ける", "Back": "たすける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "唯", "Back": "ただ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦い", "Back": "たたかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戦う", "Back": "たたかう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叩く", "Back": "たたく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直ちに", "Back": "ただちに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立ち上がる", "Back": "たちあがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立場", "Back": "たちば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経つ", "Back": "たつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "達する", "Back": "たっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縦", "Back": "たて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "谷", "Back": "たに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "他人", "Back": "たにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "種", "Back": "たね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "束", "Back": "たば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "度", "Back": "たび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旅", "Back": "たび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "多分", "Back": "たぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "玉", "Back": "たま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弾", "Back": "たま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偶", "Back": "たま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偶々", "Back": "たまたま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "黙る", "Back": "だまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "駄目", "Back": "だめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "試し", "Back": "ためし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "試す", "Back": "ためす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "便り", "Back": "たより", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頼る", "Back": "たよる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誰か", "Back": "だれか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "段", "Back": "だん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単位", "Back": "たんい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単語", "Back": "たんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "男子", "Back": "だんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単純", "Back": "たんじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誕生", "Back": "たんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "団体", "Back": "だんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "担当", "Back": "たんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単なる", "Back": "たんなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単に", "Back": "たんに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地", "Back": "ち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地位", "Back": "ちい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地域", "Back": "ちいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知恵", "Back": "ちえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地下", "Back": "ちか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "違い", "Back": "ちがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "違いない", "Back": "ちがいない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近頃", "Back": "ちかごろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地球", "Back": "ちきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地区", "Back": "ちく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遅刻", "Back": "ちこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知事", "Back": "ちじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知識", "Back": "ちしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "父親", "Back": "ちちおや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知能", "Back": "ちのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地平線", "Back": "ちへいせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地方", "Back": "ちほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茶", "Back": "ちゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中", "Back": "ちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "注", "Back": "ちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中央", "Back": "ちゅうおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中学", "Back": "ちゅうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中古", "Back": "ちゅうこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中止", "Back": "ちゅうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "駐車", "Back": "ちゅうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昼食", "Back": "ちゅうしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中心", "Back": "ちゅうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "注目", "Back": "ちゅうもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "注文", "Back": "ちゅうもん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長期", "Back": "ちょうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調査", "Back": "ちょうさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調子", "Back": "ちょうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頂上", "Back": "ちょうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貯金", "Back": "ちょきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直接", "Back": "ちょくせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "著者", "Back": "ちょしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遂に", "Back": "ついに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通過", "Back": "つうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通学", "Back": "つうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通行", "Back": "つうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通じる", "Back": "つうじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通信", "Back": "つうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕まる", "Back": "つかまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掴む", "Back": "つかむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "疲れ", "Back": "つかれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月", "Back": "つき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付き合い", "Back": "つきあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "次々", "Back": "つぎつぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "就く", "Back": "つく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付ける", "Back": "つける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土", "Back": "つち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "続き", "Back": "つづき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "包み", "Back": "つつみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勤め", "Back": "つとめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "務め", "Back": "つとめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繋ぐ", "Back": "つなぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "常に", "Back": "つねに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "翼", "Back": "つばさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "罪", "Back": "つみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詰める", "Back": "つめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "積もる", "Back": "つもる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "梅雨", "Back": "つゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辛い", "Back": "つらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "釣", "Back": "つり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連れ", "Back": "つれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出会い", "Back": "であい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出会う", "Back": "であう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "提案", "Back": "ていあん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定期", "Back": "ていき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抵抗", "Back": "ていこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "提出", "Back": "ていしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "程度", "Back": "ていど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "停留所", "Back": "ていりゅうじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敵", "Back": "てき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出来事", "Back": "できごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適する", "Back": "てきする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適切", "Back": "てきせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適度", "Back": "てきど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適用", "Back": "てきよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "できる", "Back": "（可能。出現。発生）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出来るだけ", "Back": "できるだけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手品", "Back": "てじな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄", "Back": "てつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "哲学", "Back": "てつがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手伝い", "Back": "てつだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徹底", "Back": "てってい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄道", "Back": "てつどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "徹夜", "Back": "てつや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "では", "Back": "では", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手間", "Back": "てま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "でも", "Back": "でも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "典型", "Back": "てんけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天候", "Back": "てんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電子", "Back": "でんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝統", "Back": "でんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天然", "Back": "てんねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問い", "Back": "とい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "党", "Back": "とう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塔", "Back": "とう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "答案", "Back": "とうあん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "どう", "Back": "（接。副）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同一", "Back": "どういつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当時", "Back": "とうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動詞", "Back": "どうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同時", "Back": "どうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "到着", "Back": "とうちゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "道徳", "Back": "どうとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "投票", "Back": "とうひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同様", "Back": "どうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同僚", "Back": "どうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通す", "Back": "とおす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "道路", "Back": "どうろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通り", "Back": "とおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通り過ぎる", "Back": "とおりすぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "都会", "Back": "とかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時", "Back": "とき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解く", "Back": "とく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毒", "Back": "どく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "得意", "Back": "とくい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "読書", "Back": "どくしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独身", "Back": "どくしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特徴", "Back": "とくちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独特", "Back": "どくとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独立", "Back": "どくりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解ける", "Back": "とける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "登山", "Back": "とざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "都市", "Back": "とし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年月", "Back": "としつき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図書", "Back": "としょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年寄", "Back": "としより", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "閉じる", "Back": "とじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "途端", "Back": "とたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土地", "Back": "とち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突然", "Back": "とつぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "届く", "Back": "とどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飛ばす", "Back": "とばす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飛び出す", "Back": "とびだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "留める", "Back": "とめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "友", "Back": "とも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "共に", "Back": "ともに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土曜", "Back": "どよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "虎", "Back": "とら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り上げる", "Back": "とりあげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "努力", "Back": "どりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "どれ", "Back": "どれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取れる", "Back": "とれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泥", "Back": "どろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "とん", "Back": "（1000", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名", "Back": "な", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内容", "Back": "ないよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仲", "Back": "なか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流す", "Back": "ながす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "半ば", "Back": "なかば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仲間", "Back": "なかま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眺め", "Back": "ながめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "眺める", "Back": "ながめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流れ", "Back": "ながれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流れる", "Back": "ながれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無し", "Back": "なし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "謎", "Back": "なぞ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "納得", "Back": "なっとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "等", "Back": "など", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何", "Back": "なに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何か", "Back": "なにか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鍋", "Back": "なべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怠ける", "Back": "なまける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "波", "Back": "なみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "涙", "Back": "なみだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悩む", "Back": "なやむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成る", "Back": "なる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縄", "Back": "なわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何で", "Back": "なんで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何でも", "Back": "なんでも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何とか", "Back": "なんとか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "似合う", "Back": "にあう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "匂い", "Back": "におい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦手", "Back": "にがて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "握る", "Back": "にぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日", "Back": "にち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日常", "Back": "にちじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日曜", "Back": "にちよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日光", "Back": "にっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日中", "Back": "にっちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日本", "Back": "にっぽん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入院", "Back": "にゅういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入学", "Back": "にゅうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入場", "Back": "にゅうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人気", "Back": "にんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人間", "Back": "にんげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抜く", "Back": "ぬく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抜ける", "Back": "ぬける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "布", "Back": "ぬの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濡れる", "Back": "ぬれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ね", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "根", "Back": "ね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "値", "Back": "ね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "願い", "Back": "ねがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "願う", "Back": "ねがう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鼠", "Back": "ねずみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "値段", "Back": "ねだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱心", "Back": "ねっしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱帯", "Back": "ねったい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱中", "Back": "ねっちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年間", "Back": "ねんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年中", "Back": "ねんじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年代", "Back": "ねんだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年齢", "Back": "ねんれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "野", "Back": "の", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "能", "Back": "のう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農家", "Back": "のうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農業", "Back": "のうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農民", "Back": "のうみん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "能力", "Back": "のうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ノー", "Back": "（no）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "残す", "Back": "のこす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "残り", "Back": "のこり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗せる", "Back": "のせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "除く", "Back": "のぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "望み", "Back": "のぞみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "望む", "Back": "のぞむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喉", "Back": "のど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伸ばす", "Back": "のばす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伸びる", "Back": "のびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "述べる", "Back": "のべる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昇る", "Back": "のぼる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "場", "Back": "ば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "はあ", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "はい", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灰", "Back": "はい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配達", "Back": "はいたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "俳優", "Back": "はいゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "墓", "Back": "はか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馬鹿", "Back": "ばか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "博士", "Back": "はかせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "計る", "Back": "はかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "履く", "Back": "はく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吐く", "Back": "はく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拍手", "Back": "はくしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "莫大", "Back": "ばくだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "爆発", "Back": "ばくはつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "博物館", "Back": "はくぶつかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "激しい", "Back": "はげしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破産", "Back": "はさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "端", "Back": "はし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始まり", "Back": "はじまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外す", "Back": "はずす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "旗", "Back": "はた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肌", "Back": "はだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裸", "Back": "はだか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "畑", "Back": "はたけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "二十", "Back": "はたち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "働き", "Back": "はたらき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発見", "Back": "はっけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発行", "Back": "はっこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発車", "Back": "はっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "罰する", "Back": "ばっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発達", "Back": "はったつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発展", "Back": "はってん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発表", "Back": "はっぴょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発明", "Back": "はつめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "話し合う", "Back": "はなしあう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "離す", "Back": "はなす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放す", "Back": "はなす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "離れる", "Back": "はなれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "羽", "Back": "はね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幅", "Back": "はば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "母親", "Back": "ははおや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "省く", "Back": "はぶく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "場面", "Back": "ばめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腹", "Back": "はら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原", "Back": "はら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "針", "Back": "はり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "張る", "Back": "はる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "番", "Back": "ばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "範囲", "Back": "はんい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反抗", "Back": "はんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "犯罪", "Back": "はんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "判断", "Back": "はんだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "犯人", "Back": "はんにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "販売", "Back": "はんばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灯", "Back": "ひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "被害", "Back": "ひがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "比較", "Back": "ひかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "轢く", "Back": "ひく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悲劇", "Back": "ひげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飛行", "Back": "ひこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膝", "Back": "ひざ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "非常", "Back": "ひじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "美人", "Back": "びじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日付", "Back": "ひづけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "必死", "Back": "ひっし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ張る", "Back": "ひっぱる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "否定", "Back": "ひてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一言", "Back": "ひとこと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人込み", "Back": "ひとごみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "等しい", "Back": "ひとしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独り", "Back": "ひとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一人一人", "Back": "ひとりひとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "批判", "Back": "ひはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "批評", "Back": "ひひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "秘密", "Back": "ひみつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "微妙", "Back": "びみょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紐", "Back": "ひも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "費用", "Back": "ひよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "表", "Back": "ひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "秒", "Back": "びょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "評価", "Back": "ひょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "表現", "Back": "ひょうげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "表情", "Back": "ひょうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平等", "Back": "びょうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "評判", "Back": "ひょうばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "表面", "Back": "ひょうめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広がる", "Back": "ひろがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瓶", "Back": "びん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "便", "Back": "びん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不", "Back": "ふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無", "Back": "ぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分", "Back": "ぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不安", "Back": "ふあん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風景", "Back": "ふうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夫婦", "Back": "ふうふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "笛", "Back": "ふえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不可", "Back": "ふか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "武器", "Back": "ぶき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "服装", "Back": "ふくそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "含む", "Back": "ふくむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "袋", "Back": "ふくろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不幸", "Back": "ふこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "節", "Back": "ふし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無事", "Back": "ぶじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不思議", "Back": "ふしぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不自由", "Back": "ふじゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夫人", "Back": "ふじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "婦人", "Back": "ふじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不正", "Back": "ふせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "防ぐ", "Back": "ふせぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不足", "Back": "ふそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "舞台", "Back": "ぶたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "双子", "Back": "ふたご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再び", "Back": "ふたたび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "普段", "Back": "ふだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縁", "Back": "ふち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打つ", "Back": "ぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物価", "Back": "ぶっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物質", "Back": "ぶっしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物理", "Back": "ぶつり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筆", "Back": "ふで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ふと", "Back": "（副）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "船", "Back": "ふね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "部分", "Back": "ぶぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不平", "Back": "ふへい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不満", "Back": "ふまん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不利", "Back": "ふり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振る", "Back": "ふる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "震える", "Back": "ふるえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "触れる", "Back": "ふれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風呂", "Back": "ふろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文", "Back": "ぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雰囲気", "Back": "ふんいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分析", "Back": "ぶんせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文明", "Back": "ぶんめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分野", "Back": "ぶんや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塀", "Back": "へい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平均", "Back": "へいきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平和", "Back": "へいわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "別に", "Back": "べつに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "減らす", "Back": "へらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "減る", "Back": "へる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "変化", "Back": "へんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勉強", "Back": "べんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "変更", "Back": "へんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弁当", "Back": "べんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方", "Back": "ほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "法", "Back": "ほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "棒", "Back": "ぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冒険", "Back": "ぼうけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方向", "Back": "ほうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "報告", "Back": "ほうこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宝石", "Back": "ほうせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放送", "Back": "ほうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "豊富", "Back": "ほうふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方法", "Back": "ほうほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訪問", "Back": "ほうもん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吠える", "Back": "ほえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外", "Back": "ほか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誇り", "Back": "ほこり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "埃", "Back": "ほこり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保証", "Back": "ほしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保存", "Back": "ほぞん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "程", "Back": "ほど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歩道", "Back": "ほどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仏", "Back": "ほとけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "骨", "Back": "ほね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炎", "Back": "ほのお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頬", "Back": "ほほ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "微笑む", "Back": "ほほえむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "褒める", "Back": "ほめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濠", "Back": "ほり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本当", "Back": "ほんと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本人", "Back": "ほんにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本物", "Back": "ほんもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間", "Back": "ま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迷子", "Back": "まいご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "任せる", "Back": "まかせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幕", "Back": "まく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "負け", "Back": "まけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "孫", "Back": "まご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真面目", "Back": "まじめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増す", "Back": "ます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先ず", "Back": "まず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貧しい", "Back": "まずしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "又", "Back": "また", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未だ", "Back": "まだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "街", "Back": "まち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間違い", "Back": "まちがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "松", "Back": "まつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ赤", "Back": "まっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ直ぐ", "Back": "まっすぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全く", "Back": "まったく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祭", "Back": "まつり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学ぶ", "Back": "まなぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真似", "Back": "まね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "招く", "Back": "まねく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "豆", "Back": "まめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "守る", "Back": "まもる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸", "Back": "まる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丸い", "Back": "まるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回す", "Back": "まわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回り", "Back": "まわり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "万一", "Back": "まんいち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満足", "Back": "まんぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身", "Back": "み", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実", "Back": "み", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見送り", "Back": "みおくり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "味方", "Back": "みかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見事", "Back": "みごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満ちる", "Back": "みちる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "密", "Back": "みつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "認める", "Back": "みとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皆", "Back": "みんな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見舞い", "Back": "みまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "土産", "Back": "みやげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "都", "Back": "みやこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妙", "Back": "みょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明後日", "Back": "みょうごにち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未来", "Back": "みらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "魅力", "Back": "みりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見る", "Back": "みる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向かい", "Back": "むかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迎え", "Back": "むかえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向く", "Back": "むく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向ける", "Back": "むける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無視", "Back": "むし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "虫歯", "Back": "むしば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寧ろ", "Back": "むしろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "結ぶ", "Back": "むすぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無駄", "Back": "むだ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夢中", "Back": "むちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "胸", "Back": "むね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無料", "Back": "むりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芽", "Back": "め", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明確", "Back": "めいかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "命じる", "Back": "めいじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名人", "Back": "めいじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "命令", "Back": "めいれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迷惑", "Back": "めいわく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飯", "Back": "めし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滅多に", "Back": "めったに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面", "Back": "めん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "綿", "Back": "めん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "免許", "Back": "めんきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面倒", "Back": "めんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し込む", "Back": "もうしこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し訳", "Back": "もうしわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毛布", "Back": "もうふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "燃える", "Back": "もえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目的", "Back": "もくてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目標", "Back": "もくひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "木曜", "Back": "もくよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文字", "Back": "もじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持ち上げる", "Back": "もちあげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用いる", "Back": "もちいる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勿論", "Back": "もちろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "最も", "Back": "もっとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尤も", "Back": "もっとも", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "元", "Back": "もと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基", "Back": "もと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素", "Back": "もと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戻す", "Back": "もどす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基づく", "Back": "もとづく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "求める", "Back": "もとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "者", "Back": "もの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物音", "Back": "ものおと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物語", "Back": "ものがたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物事", "Back": "ものごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "模様", "Back": "もよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貰う", "Back": "もらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文句", "Back": "もんく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役", "Back": "やく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "約", "Back": "やく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訳", "Back": "やく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役割", "Back": "やくわり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家賃", "Back": "やちん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厄介", "Back": "やっかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宿", "Back": "やど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雇う", "Back": "やとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屋根", "Back": "やね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破る", "Back": "やぶる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "辞める", "Back": "やめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "唯一", "Back": "ゆいいつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勇気", "Back": "ゆうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有効", "Back": "ゆうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優秀", "Back": "ゆうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "優勝", "Back": "ゆうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "友情", "Back": "ゆうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "友人", "Back": "ゆうじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有能", "Back": "ゆうのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "郵便", "Back": "ゆうびん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夕べ", "Back": "ゆうべ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有利", "Back": "ゆうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "床", "Back": "ゆか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "愉快", "Back": "ゆかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輸出", "Back": "ゆしゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "譲る", "Back": "ゆずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "豊か", "Back": "ゆたか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輸入", "Back": "ゆにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "許す", "Back": "ゆるす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜", "Back": "よ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜明け", "Back": "よあけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "様", "Back": "よう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酔う", "Back": "よう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "容易", "Back": "ようい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陽気", "Back": "ようき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要求", "Back": "ようきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用心", "Back": "ようじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "様子", "Back": "ようす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要するに", "Back": "ようするに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要素", "Back": "ようそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要点", "Back": "ようてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曜日", "Back": "ようび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予期", "Back": "よき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "横切る", "Back": "よこぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予算", "Back": "よさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "止す", "Back": "よす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予測", "Back": "よそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜中", "Back": "よなか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "世の中", "Back": "よのなか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余分", "Back": "よぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予報", "Back": "よほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予防", "Back": "よぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "読み", "Back": "よみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嫁", "Back": "よめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余裕", "Back": "よゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "喜び", "Back": "よろこび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宜しい", "Back": "よろしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "よろしく", "Back": "（感）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "来", "Back": "らい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "楽", "Back": "らく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利益", "Back": "りえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "理解", "Back": "りかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陸", "Back": "りく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利口", "Back": "りこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "離婚", "Back": "りこん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "理想", "Back": "りそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "率", "Back": "りつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立派", "Back": "りっぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "留学", "Back": "りゅうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流行", "Back": "りゅうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "量", "Back": "りょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "両替", "Back": "りょうがえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "料金", "Back": "りょうきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "例", "Back": "れい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "礼", "Back": "れい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "礼儀", "Back": "れいぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷静", "Back": "れいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "列", "Back": "れつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "列車", "Back": "れっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "練習", "Back": "れんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連想", "Back": "れんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連続", "Back": "れんぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "老人", "Back": "ろうじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "労働", "Back": "ろうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "論じる", "Back": "ろんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "論争", "Back": "ろんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "論文", "Back": "ろんぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輪", "Back": "わ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "別れ", "Back": "わかれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脇", "Back": "わき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分ける", "Back": "わける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "僅か", "Back": "わずか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "話題", "Back": "わだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "笑い", "Back": "わらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割る", "Back": "わる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悪口", "Back": "わるくち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "我々", "Back": "われわれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湾", "Back": "わん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n3-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{}]
